Brendan Howe

(510) 701-5895 Seattle, WA

brendan.howe1@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/bhowe111

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/brendan-howe/</u>

A full-stack junior web developer, experienced in gathering, analyzing and compiling information from disparate resources into engaging products. My background in the service industry, education and nonprofit radio informs my problem-solving approach of doing more with less.

------ CHANGES TO BE MADE FOR GA EXP -------

Skills and languages

React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, jQuery, Node, Express, MongoDB, SASS, GitHub,

Projects and experience

GitHub

Education

General Assembly SEI Boot Camp, 12 week, 450+ hour

Revisions

- 1. Reformat resume to have sidebar and project links, updated style
- 2. Areas of strength: Concise, flowing sections. White space
- 3. Reformatting would make it more impactful. Removing extraneous experience, cutting to one page
- 4. Getting through the ATS first with keywords, then elaborating in interviews

----- BEGINNING OF CURRENT RESUME ------

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Brendan Howe Communications • Seattle, WA • January 2016–Present *Freelance Writer, Editor, and Interviewer*

Write and edit articles for a range of clients focusing on innovation in the arts, including:

- Chamber Music Magazine New York, NY
- KING FM 98.1 Seattle, WA
- Live Music Project Seattle, WA
- VAN Magazine Berlin, Germany
- Logic 20/20 Seattle, WA

Classical KING FM 98.1 • Seattle, WA • January 2017–February 2018

Brendan Howe

brendan@brendanhowe.net

Community Outreach Coordinator

- Cultivate relationships with 28 local arts organizations and assist with contract negotiations, providing KING FM Programming greater flexibility and control over content.
- Manage 30+ KING FM volunteers.
- Coordinate KING FM publicity and presence at 120+ events per year.
- Organize volunteer appreciation events.
- Host for KING FM's 24/7 contemporary music stream Second Inversion.

Multi-Service Center (MSC) • Federal Way, WA • January–July 2016

Education Support Specialist

- Oversaw 12 volunteers who supported MSC's Employment and Education staff, educating them on resources available to MSC clients (e.g., food bank and literacy classes).
- Ran outreach events to reach new clients in need of MSC services; recruited over 20 clients in two months.

National Public Radio KCRW 89.9 FM • Los Angeles, CA • May–August 2015

Outreach Intern

Recruited 55 new public radio members, cultivated donor relationships, and promoted station events.

Advance ESL Academy • Berkeley, CA • May 2014–January 2015

Instructor for Test of English as a Foreign Language (TOEFL)

• Developed curriculum for TOEFL students. Prepared 15 students for their English test, raising their TOEFL class readiness from 8 to 93% over six months.

Refúgio ESL • Rio de Janeiro, Brazil • October 2013–April 2014

ESL Instructor

• Gave private English lessons to 15 staff at Refúgio Hostel in Rio de Janeiro.

University of California, Santa Cruz • Santa Cruz, CA • September 2012–January 2013 *Instructional Assistant*

• Worked with the core professor on curriculum and teaching methods for a freshman writing course. Ran bi-weekly writing workshops for 18 students, raising scores by an average of 30%.

RETAIL EXPERIENCE

Momosan • Seattle, WA • August 2019–present Shift Lead

Original staff member of Iron Chef Morimoto's Ramen and Sake concept restaurant.

Brendan Howe

brendan@brendanhowe.net

- Present knowledge of sake and food pairings in an engaging, accessible manner.
- Turn over 20+ seat sections rapidly for several hours.

Tutta Bella Neapolitan Pizzeria, Cascabel, Paper or Plastik Cafe • June 2014–July 2019 Lead Server

- Manage front of house operations with efficiency, clear communication and compassion.
- Settle finances each shift, write daily recaps to keep management informed on staff performance, customer comments, as well as hard data such as sales and labor costs.

Counterpoint Records and Books • Hollywood, CA • July 2015–January 2016 *Customer Service Representative*

- Evaluated used books and records brought to the store and decided which ones to add to inventory.
- Reorganized stocking system to refine physical search process for thousands of books and records.

EDUCATION

September 2009–June 2013 University of California, Santa Cruz • Santa Cruz, CA

• Bachelor of Arts in American Studies with honors in the major